<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Projects - Category - Roberto Aguilar</title>
        <link>https://robguilar.com/categories/projects/</link>
        <description>Projects - Category - Roberto Aguilar</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>This work is developed and posted only under Rob&#39;s property</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 21:57:40 &#43;0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://robguilar.com/categories/projects/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Tactical Analytics: A/B Testing with Cookie Cats Game</title>
    <link>https://robguilar.com/posts/ab_testing_cookiecats/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 21:57:40 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://robguilar.com/posts/ab_testing_cookiecats/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[What are Tactical Analytics? A type of user-oriented game analytics, with the purpose to &ldquo;aim to inform game design at the short-term, for example, an A/B test of a new game feature&rdquo; (A. Dranchen, 2013).
The applicability of statistics in new fields can be considered as one of the greatest advances for humanity. Nowadays, human-machine interactions are being monitored, in a good way in most cases.
The main purpose is not just to increase the companies revenue, one of the main objectives is to give a benefit in terms of User Experience (UX) and Engagement, and this can be covered using Data Science.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Video Games History plugged by Data</title>
    <link>https://robguilar.com/posts/evga/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 21:57:40 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://robguilar.com/posts/evga/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>The industry of video games revenues is reaching the $173.7 billion in value, with around 2.5 billion users enjoying them worldwide, with a forecasted value of $314.40 billion by 2026 according to Mordor Intelligence.</p>
<p>Impressive facts, right? Nowadays this market is no longer considered a simple hobby for kids, it has become a constantly growing giant which attracts more and more customers as it takes advantage of the growth of streaming platforms. But this industry, as we well know, is taking more fields, born from ambitious expectations such as the Nintendo World Championships in the 90&rsquo;s to what today many have adopted as a lifestyle also known as <i>Esports</i>.</p>]]></description>
</item></channel>
</rss>
