<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Big Data - Tag - Roberto Aguilar Portfolio</title>
        <link>https://robguilar.com/tags/big-data/</link>
        <description>Big Data - Tag - Roberto Aguilar Portfolio</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>This work is developed and posted only under Roberto&#39;s property</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Nov 2021 21:57:40 &#43;0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://robguilar.com/tags/big-data/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Cloud Service Architecture for NLP in Google Cloud</title>
    <link>https://robguilar.com/posts/gcp_academicsolution/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 04 Nov 2021 21:57:40 &#43;0800</pubDate><guid>https://robguilar.com/posts/gcp_academicsolution/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<h3 id="summary">Summary:</h3>
<ul>
<li>
<p>This academic article was developed through my postgraduate course, <i>DAT-03 Data Analysis in Big Data Environments</i>, which presents a business case in which a company is interested in combining and migrating relational databases in <b>Microsoft SQL Server</b> and <b>Oracle DB</b>. Given the need to feed them with an NLP system output of social networks such as Instagram, Telegram, and Facebook Messenger.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Initially, the vulnerabilities that the company has when managing its data in a Local Storage are shown, where it is compared with the advantages of implementing a <b>Cloud Service</b>. This service is compared with others such as Microsoft Azure and Amazon Cloud Services, showing why this solution is the one that best suits the business case.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>An architecture diagram was designed, covering the required APIs to the ingestion, storage, processing, and loading of the data in BI tools to ease access to the end-user.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Finally, financial aspects are covered in terms of operating costs for the proposed solution.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<p>In case you want to access it, next you will find a link where it was uploaded to my LinkedIn. Click <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/robguilarr/overlay/1635470662045/single-media-viewer/">HERE</a> to access or download.</p>
<hr>
<p align=center>
    <a class="lightgallery" href="/images/posts/gcpcover.jpg" title="/images/posts/gcpcover.jpg" data-thumbnail="/images/posts/gcpcover.jpg">
        
    </a>
</p>
]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
