<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Roberto Aguilar</title>
        <link>https://robguilar.com/</link>
        <description>Welcome to Roberto&#39;s portfolio website, through this portal you will be able to see his most recent content &amp; projects published</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>This work is developed and posted only under Roberto&#39;s property</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 May 2022 21:57:40 &#43;0800</lastBuildDate>
            <atom:link href="https://robguilar.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
    <title>Inspecting Control Mechanics using T-Tests on Fallout New Vegas</title>
    <link>https://robguilar.com/posts/control_mechanics_fallout/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2022 21:57:40 &#43;0800</pubDate><guid>https://robguilar.com/posts/control_mechanics_fallout/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[The plot of the sequel of Fallout 3 takes context in the year 2281, 4 years after the first escape from Vault 101, within a post-apocalyptic world after the Great War.
This RPG has an open world inspired by cities such as Nevada, California, Arizona, and Utah, allowing users to have a large number of places to explore and a world with NPCs to interact with, ideal for developing behavioral and exploratory analysis.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Leveling Difficulty in Candy Crush Saga</title>
    <link>https://robguilar.com/posts/candy_crush_difficulty/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 21:57:40 &#43;0800</pubDate><guid>https://robguilar.com/posts/candy_crush_difficulty/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Today&rsquo;s analysis will lead us to a world fulfilled with divine puzzle adventures at the side of Tiffi and Mr. Toffee, in which we&rsquo;ll glimpse the success rate of more than 6800 peers with eagerness for treats.
The game is Candy Crush Saga a record-breaking mobile game developed by King, a subsidiary of Activision Blizzard since 2016.
In terms of its gameplay, this game used to have a total of 816 episodes, until one of the major add-ons was removed (Dreamworld).]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>A/B Testing with Cookie Cats Game</title>
    <link>https://robguilar.com/posts/ab_testing_cookiecats/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 21:57:40 &#43;0800</pubDate><guid>https://robguilar.com/posts/ab_testing_cookiecats/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[A lot of things come to mind when we hear the name Cookie Cats, and probably is not what we think since is hard to associate both words, it’s about meow-sicians (Belle, Ziggy, Smokey, Rita, Berry).
Anyway, Cookie Cats is a mobile puzzle game of “connect-three”-style developed by Tactile Entertainment, a mobile games developer from Copenhagen. To be in context, this game’s main objective is to align 3 cookies of the same kind to feed a cat, and in this way finish each level.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Video Games History explained with Pandas</title>
    <link>https://robguilar.com/posts/evga/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 21:57:40 &#43;0800</pubDate><guid>https://robguilar.com/posts/evga/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>The industry of video games revenues is reaching the $173.7 billion in value, with around 2.5 billion users enjoying them worldwide, with a forecasted value of $314.40 billion by 2026 according to Mordor Intelligence.</p>
<p>Impressive facts, right? Nowadays this market is no longer considered a simple hobby for kids, it has become a constantly growing giant which attracts more and more customers as it takes advantage of the growth of streaming platforms. But this industry, as we well know, is taking more fields, born from ambitious expectations such as the Nintendo World Championships in the 90&rsquo;s to what today many have adopted as a lifestyle also known as <i>Esports</i>.</p>
<p>In this exploratory analysis, we will also see one of the events that marked the industry in the 80s. Here is a preview.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Game Development Team Structure</title>
    <link>https://robguilar.com/posts/gamedev_structure/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 21:57:40 &#43;0800</pubDate><guid>https://robguilar.com/posts/gamedev_structure/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[In the next portal, you will find a frame with a diagram. This one displays the distinct roles and sub-roles in a video game development team.
This section intends that as you read the Stakeholders section in each of my projects, you can learn about the operations, roles, and skills that each team member must possess. For this, you can read the details at the bottom of the card made for each.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Cloud Service Architecture for NLP in Google Cloud</title>
    <link>https://robguilar.com/posts/gcp_academicsolution/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 21:57:40 &#43;0800</pubDate><guid>https://robguilar.com/posts/gcp_academicsolution/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Summary:   This academic article was developed through my postgraduate course, DAT-03 Data Analysis in Big Data Environments, which presents a business case in which a company is interested in combining and migrating relational databases in Microsoft SQL Server and Oracle DB. Given the need to feed them with an NLP system output of social networks such as Instagram, Telegram, and Facebook Messenger.
  Initially, the vulnerabilities that the company has when managing its data in a Local Storage are shown, where it is compared with the advantages of implementing a Cloud Service.]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
